# 炸酱你看有的人加水
When making the "zhajiang" ("fried sauce"), some people will add water
# 咱们一点水不澥 这叫润
We are not adding any water, just thinning the sauce with other ingredients
# 好香啊
Smells amazing
# 我炸酱的时候用三种酱
When I fry the black bean sauce I use 3 different kinds of sauces
# 这是干黄酱
This is "ganhuangjiang" ("dry yellow soybean sauce")
# 你闻闻这个
You smell this one
# 这个（黄豆）酱呢 非常甜
This (soybean) sauce is very sweet
# 这个甜度大 当什么使 当糖使
It is so sweet that we can use it as sugar
# 咱就不用放糖了
Now we don’t need to add sugar
# 咱就都放里边 行了
We just add them all in there
# 咱就别给人糟践了
So that it can't be wasted by other people
# 这儿还有一种酱 这个也香
Here is another sauce, also smells very good
# 这三种酱合一
We mix all these 3 kinds of sauce together
# 我拿黄酒 我师父这就不一样了
I am adding Huangjiu. Master is cooking it differently
# 加的黄酒 黄酒澥
We added Huangjiu to thin it down
# 要咱家的料酒行不行 料酒不好
Can we add regular cooking wine? Cooking wine is not good
# 料酒它有点那个味道
Cooking wine has a special taste
# 还不如不放 你要放料酒
If you have regular cooking wine, I rather not to add any of it
# 就买那不到十块钱的花雕酒就完全可以
Just add the cheap Huadiao rice wine which is less than 10 cny
# 朝晖再拿点酱油来
Chaohui bring me more soy sauce
# 普通酱油 咱来澥一澥
Just regular soy sauce, add some to thin it down
# 倒进去没事儿
Just add it in, it’s fine
# 倒了稀稠合适就行
Thin it down to the right consistency
# 这就差不多了
This is about it
# 你看有好多 炸出酱来
You know, when many people fry this zhajiang
# 炸到什么份上了
Do you know how long they fry it?
# 炸的真跟黑了吧唧的 干的
They fry until the sauce is black and dry
# 那就不对 也就不好吃了
It is wrong and it is not going to taste good
# 因为炸的酱首先要润
When frying the sauce, first we need to make the sauce moist
# 这基本就差不多了
We are almost done
# 网友们 看看稀稠度啊 稀稠度 行了
Guys let’s see this consistency, the consistency is right here
# 咱就开始开火
Let’s turn on the heat
# 师父这个火调多大
Master how high should it be
# 大点 越大越好 好嘞 大火啊
High, the higher the better
# 你说为什么加这黄豆酱
You know why we need to add soybean sauce
# 这个酱 如果说要没有糖的甜度
This sauce, if there is no certain sweetness in the sauce
# 这酱吃起来 寡 干 干咸干咸的
It will taste bland and dry, dry and salty
# 吃起来不柔
It is not soft and smooth when you eat it
# 炸出来酱就不好吃 你知道吗
Frying the sauce that way is not going to taste good you know?
# 锅热了师父 锅热了没事儿
The wok is hot now master. Wok is hot, cool
# 就这点油吧 够了
Just adding this much oil will be enough
# 这简单说一下
I just gonna elaborate a little
# 这为什么说 这个酒店要炸的好吃呢
Do you know why the restaurant fries better sauce
# 我们用的油 是不用这种油
The oil we using is not regular oil
# 用什么油做 你知道吗
Do you know what oil we use？
# 用葱烧海参的葱油
We use oil fried with scallion and sea cucumber
# 然后用这葱油 炸这酱 煸这肉
And the fried the sauce and the meat with that oil
# 一听就香
It sound very tasty
# 今天咱就不再做葱油了
Today we are not going to make scallion oil
# 因为这做葱油 做了好几回了
Because we have made this scallion oil multiple times
# 网友也知道怎么做了
Audiences know how to make it already
# 能搁多少搁多少
We will add as much as we can
# 都搁里头得了
Well might as well add them all
# 好家伙 这多少肉啊
Oh well this is a lot of meat
# 就爱吃炸酱里边的肉
I love the meat from the fried bean sauce
# 炸酱里边就得有肥肉 要不然不香
And there must be some fat meat, otherwise it won’t smell good
# 这肉呢 多煸煸它
We are going to fry this meat for a bit longer
# 让它把这水气出来 这香气就过来了
Fry all the water out of the sauce, then it will smell really good
# 你看到了没有 这里边有水 是吧
You see now, there is  water in it, right?
# 你要这样炒出酱来 肯定就发闷
If you going to fry the sauce with this it will not taste good
# 这肉就不好吃了 不香
The meat will not taste good, and will not smell good
# 它必须把这水气出去
We must vaporize the water
# 水气出去 这个猪油也熬出来了
When we fry the water out of it, we also fry the oil out of the meat
# 熬出来了它香啊
Fry them long enough, the aromatic of the ingredients all comes out
# 师姐您在家做炸酱吗
Sister do you fry sauce at home?
# 做啊 这是我们家的传统保留节目
Yeah definitely, this is the tradition in our family
# 这个可以一锅多炸点
We can fry a little bit more sauce in the wok
# 然后分瓶装了以后搁冰箱里存着
And then split them into several bottles and put them in the refrigerator
# 想吃的时候 微波炉一热
When you feel like having it, just heat it up with microwave
# 这肉就差不多了 咱可以了
The meat is almost done, we are almost finished
# 师父您再说说
Master can you elaborate more
# 这个炸到什么情况下算是好了
How to tell when it is done?
# 你看这油 油清亮了
You look at the oil, the oil is clear
# 这肉四边已经有小的焦质了
The meat is browning around the edges
# 但是里边还是嫩的
But still tender on the inside
# 第一遍葱 这咱们第一遍葱
Now let’s add the first round of scallions
# 咱们第一遍葱弄大点
First round let’s add a larger amount
# 这要是拿葱油炸的话就更香了
If we are using the scallion oil it will smell better
# 因为葱油里边含有香菜啊 还有香料
Because the scallion oil has cilantro and other herb
# 师父 这会儿咱们下酱吗  可以下了
Master, can we add the sauce now? Yes we can
# 这葱味的香气就出来了 不能炸糊了
Now you can smell the aromatic of the scallion, we can not over fry it
# 因为它还有一个过程呢 真地道
Because there is still a procedure later. Very authentic
# 你看这颜色
You look at this color
# 为什么我说这酱不能加水吧
This is why I said that we couldn’t add water
# 加酱油都没事
It’s okay if you add soy sauce
# 把整个这个酱香味都给弄出来了
We are extracting all the flavor out of the sauce
# 这得推四十分钟呢 推稠了它
We need to mix it for 40 mins, thicken the sauce a little
# 香味出来了
Now we can smell the aromatic
# 这个香味跟平时炸酱香味不一样
This fragrance is different from normal regular sauce
# 师父这个酱咱们炸了半个小时了
We have been frying for 30mins
# 也差不多了
We are almost there
# 咱们把多的油  这是肉里边的油
Now we are putting away these extra oil from meat
# 一会咱炒菜使 这炒菜香啊
We will use it to stir fry dishes, it will very tasty
# 师父这个葱咱们是一会再放是吧
Master are we putting the scallions in later?
# 咱们第一次下葱了吧
You see we have put the first round of scallions in previously
# 你看 这师父的窍门儿
Look at my technique
# 第二次下葱 最后还有第三次
This is the second batch of scallion, later we are adding the third batch
# 我是三次下葱
I am adding scallions in 3 separate times
# 再开大点火
Turn the heat up a little bit
# 看看 这火 稍微开大点
See, we are turning the heat up a little bit
# 你看 香气都出来了是吧
You see we can smell the aromatic
# 稠度也够了
Thickness is good
# 这个可以下第三次葱了
Now we can add the third batch of scallions
# 一开始还是清香的
At first it is refreshing fragrance
# 现在就是这种醇厚的酱香
Now it is thick sauce aromatic
# 有点扒锅的感觉那种味道出来了
The sauce is thickened and have a feeling of sticking to the wok
# 是吧 香气都带出来了
Right, bring out the aromatic
# 咱这就差不多了啊
We are almost done
# 好嘞 关火
Alright now, turn off the heat
# 师父您㨤一勺慢慢往下流
Master you pick up a scoop and let it fall down slowly
# 我照照这感觉
Let me film this
# 哎呦喂 好 太棒了
Great
# 这叫润 是不是照照就知道了
This is moisture, you can tell from the look
# 好香啊
Smells so good
# 咱们今天因为时间原因 面咱就不吃了
Today we don’t have much time, so we are not having it with noodles
# 但是咱有
But we have(cucumber)
# 哈喇子都快流出来了
Saliva is coming out
# 给你俩一人来一筷子
I will give you each a big scoop
# 师姐 好嘞谢谢
Sister Great Thanks
# 上来就弄一大肉丁啊
Here is a big scoop of diced meat
# 你们得尝尝这肉怎么回事
You need to taste the meat
# 肉炸到什么份上 这是关键
To what extent we need to fry the meat, that’s the key
# 包括肉的嫩度的感觉 那个香气
And how tender the meat is, how to bring out the aromatic
# 这个酱 它是不可分开的
This sauce, they are inseparable
# 师父一会儿我打包啊
Master I am going to take it to go
# 这个可以了 惦记半天了
Okay, you have been thinking about it don’t you